Benjamin J. Weiner Curriculum Vitae March 20, 2017

Address: Steward Observatory, Dept. of Astronomy, University of Arizona, 933 N. Cherry St., Tucson, AZ 85721, USA. Telephone: 520.621.4119, email: bjw@as.arizona.edu, web: http://mingus.as.arizona.edu/~bjw

Role in the Project: Expertise on spatially resolved imaging and spectroscopy with HST and preparation for JWST proposals. Measurement of far-infrared SEDs and star formation rates. Radio and millimeter observations including ALMA. Spatially resolved kinematics.

Current Position:

Associate Astronomer and Staff Scientist, MMT Observatory, University of Arizona, 2017 – present

Previous Positions:

Associate Astronomer, Steward Observatory, University of Arizona, 2013 – present

Assistant Astronomer, Steward Observatory, University of Arizona, 2006 – 2013

Postdoctoral researcher, supervisor S. Veilleux, University of Maryland, 2004 – 2006

Postdoctoral researcher, supervisor S. Faber, University of California at Santa Cruz, 2000 – 2004 Barbara McClintock Postdoctoral Fellow, Carnegie Observatories, 1998 – 2000

Education:

Swarthmore College, Physics and English Literature, B.A. 1989

Rutgers University, Astrophysics, Ph.D. 1998

Committee Service: Beatrice Tinsley Prize Committee, American Astronomical Society

Selected Publications:

- C. Pacifici, S.A. Kassin, B.J. Weiner, et al. 2016, "The Evolution of Star Formation Histories of Quiescent Galaxies," ApJ, 832, 79
- J.S. Spilker, R. Bezanson, D.P. Marrone, B.J. Weiner, K.E. Whitaker, C.C. Williams, 2016, "Low Gas Fractions Connect Compact Star-forming Galaxies to Their $z \sim 2$ Quiescent Descendants," ApJ, 832, 19
- R.C. Simons, S.A. Kassin, J.R. Trump, B.J. Weiner et al. 2016, "Kinematic Downsizing at $z\sim 2$," ApJ, 830, 14
- R.C. Simons, S.A. Kassin, B.J. Weiner et al. 2016, "A transition mass in the local Tully-Fisher relation," MNRAS, 452, 986
- A.M. Morris, D.D. Kocevski, J.R. Trump, B.J. Weiner et al. 2015, "A WFC3 Grism Emission Line Redshift Catalog in the GOODS-South Field," AJ, 149, 178
- R. Genzel et al. 2015, "Combined CO and Dust Scaling Relations of Depletion Time and Molecular Gas Fractions with Cosmic Time, Specific Star-formation Rate, and Stellar Mass," ApJ, 800, 20
- T. Dolley, M.J.I. Brown, B.J. Weiner et al. 2014, "The Clustering and Halo Masses of Star-forming Galaxies at z<1," ApJ, 797, 125
- F. Walter et al. 2014, "A Molecular Line Scan in the Hubble Deep Field North: Constraints on the CO Luminosity Function and the Cosmic H_2 Density," ApJ, 782, 79
- J.A. Newman et al. 2013, "The DEEP2 Galaxy Redshift Survey: Design, Observations, Data Reduction, and Redshifts," ApJS, 208, 5
- C. Pacifici, S.A. Kassin, B.J. Weiner, S. Charlot, J.P. Gardner. 2013, "The Rise and Fall of the Star Formation Histories of Blue Galaxies at Redshifts 0.2 < z < 1.4," ApJL, 762, L15
- W. Rujopakarn, G.H. Rieke, B.J. Weiner, P. Perez-Gonzalez, M. Rex, G.L. Walth, J.S. Kartaltepe. 2013, "Mid-infrared Determination of Total Infrared Luminosity and Star Formation Rates of Local and High-redshift Galaxies," ApJ, 767, 73
- L.J. Tacconi et al. 2013, "Phibss: Molecular Gas Content and Scaling Relations in $z \sim 1-3$ Massive, Main-sequence Star-forming Galaxies," ApJ, 768, 74
 - S.A. Kassin, B.J. Weiner, et al. 2012, "The Epoch of Disk Settling: $z \sim 1$ to Now," ApJ, 758, 106
- K.H.R. Rubin, B.J. Weiner, et al. 2010, "The Persistence of Cool Galactic Winds in High Stellar Mass Galaxies between $z \sim 1.4$ and 1," ApJ, 719, 1503
- B.J. Weiner et al. 2009, "Ubiquitous Outflows in DEEP2 Spectra of Star-Forming Galaxies at z=1.4," ApJ, 692, 187
- K.G. Noeske, B.J. Weiner, et al. 2007, "Star Formation in AEGIS Field Galaxies since z=1.1: The Dominance of Gradually Declining Star Formation, and the Main Sequence of Star-forming Galaxies," ApJL, 660, L43